wojciech(@at)zankowski.ch https://github.com/WojciechZankowski https://www.zankowski.ch



Self-driven, passionate and committed software engineer specializing in market trading and asset management discipline. Flexible with

languages, tools and everything that leads to good solution. Enjoying his life in the beautiful area of Zürich.



### **EMPLOYMENT**

#### Vice President, Credit Suisse AG

2022-03 — Present | Zürich, Switzerland

Technology: Java SE 17, Spring Boot, OpenAPI, Apache Kafka, GraphQL,

International Wealth Management

• Platform modernization and consolidation

#### Lead Software Engineer, Luxoft Financial Services AG (for Credit Suisse AG)

2019-09 — 2022-02 | Zürich, Switzerland

#### Senior Software Engineer

2019-04 — 2019-08 | Zürich, Switzerland

#### Senior Software Engineer

2018-10 — 2019-03 | Wroclaw, Poland

#### Software Engineer

2017-08 — 2018-10 | Wroclaw, Poland

**Technology:** Java SE 8, Java EE, Google Guice, Google Guava, Hibernate, Oracle DB, Angular 4+, Typescript, D3.js, AngularJS, Enterprise Architect, JProfiler, Liquibase, Splunk,

International Wealth Management - Portfolio Solutions

- Technical Leadership for a team of 6 Full-Stack Developers, 2 Business Analysts and 1 QA tester
- Technical leadership, designing & development of Client-ready Portfolio Opportunity generation project, Sustainable Investing initiative, Transaction Applicability project and tailored-made process for Premium Clients
- Development and maintenance of suite of Portfolio Solutions applications in Private Banking 360° Advisory Process, BookBuilder and Portfolio Advisory & Monitoring
- Leading Neue Aargauer Bank migration
- $\bullet \quad \text{Introducing integration test framework with usage of WireMock} \\$
- Development and maintenance of client facing Robo-Advisory application in Private Banking 360° Advisory
  Process. Building application from the scratch with all core functionalities like Client Information, Portfolio
  Analysis, Portfolio Optimization and Regulatory features.

#### Software Engineer, Empirica S.A.

2015-07 — 2017-08 | Wroclaw, Poland

**Technology:** Java SE 8, FIX 4.2/5.0 Protocol, Java Swing, Spring Framework, Spring Boot, MySQL, Chronicle, Hudson, Eclipse MAT, VisualVM, JConsole, Hibernate, AngularJS,

Algorithmic Trading Platform

- Order Engine, Portfolio Monitoring, Strategy Executor and Backtesting platform development
- Trading strategies implementation for market makers
- FIX Brokers integration, e.g. Interactive Brokers
- Market Data Feeds integration, e.g. Oanda, Interactive Brokers
- System maintenance

#### Robo Advisory Platform

- Implementation of portfolio re-balancing logic, building REST and Web Socket services
- Defining specification for Robo-Advisory platform

- Taking part in system architecture and planning integrations with external systems
- Leading project and determining requirements for development team
- Contact with clients and taking part in client meetings
- Leading Scrum ceremonies: backlog refinement, sprint planning



#### Backend



#### Frontend



#### Tools



#### Other





# **PROJECTS**

#### **IEXTrading4j**

2017-03 — Present

IEX Trading allows to receive market and financial data. Their data can be accessed in real-time during market session, can be downloaded as recorded sessions in PCAP files or can be accessed by bunch of different API-s. Ecosystem of libraries allows to access each type of data from binary packets, REST, SSE or Websocket services.



### **CERTIFICATES**

**Oracle Certified Professional: Java SE 17 Developer** 

**Oracle Certified Professional: Java SE 11 Developer** 2021-04



### **EDUCATION**

### Bachelor of Science in Systems Engineering, Wroclaw University of Science and Technology

2012-10 — 2016-01

Faculty is teaching how to use the information tools, including writing simple programs, desiging data bases and active use of the Internet resources. The studies program involves elements of microeconomy, secrets of managing enterprise finances or the selected issues of market economy. They learn basics in law - especially in the civil law part, economic circulation, competition and consumer protection or intellectual and industrial property protection.



## **LANGUAGES**

English Sp

Spanish German Polish
Fluent Basic Native



# **TESTIMONIALS**

#### Jakub Bączkiewicz - Senior Software QA @ Capgemini

Wojciech is a role model both in IT world and private life. He has outstanding knowledge regarding programming and software development and is a natural-born leader. He is passionate about what he is doing and always takes responsibility for his and he's team decisions. He has clear vision of the projects he's working in, persistently pursues his goals and makes impossible - possible. I strongly recommend him as your future coworker, teammate and leader.

#### Patryk Stopyra - Security Developer @ UBS

What is most characteristic for him - it's his engagement. When he obtains a problem to be solved - he focuses on it, gets 100% involved into the subject and does not give up until he comes out with an accurate solution. And he is usually extremely efficient with this.